Alex Lewis

(270) 799 – 5591 | alex.lewis@gmail.com | Portfolio: https://pure-spire-68655.herokuapp.com/ | https://github.com/Skymx99

Summary of Qualifications

A Junior Full Stack Developer with experience working with various web development technologies and mobile app creation. Well versed in front-end / back-end development, and graphic design creating a unique set of skills that bridge the gap between designers and programmers.

Education

Covalence Coding Bootcamp (Jan. 2018 – Mar. 2018)

Full Stack Development Certification Experience building web applications, mobile apps, databases, and backend APIs (Mar. 2018)

Western Kentucky University

B.S. Systems Management (2011)

Projects

React-Native

Developed a native app for iOS and Android using the Agile methodology in a team environment. The app utilized many native components that allows users to sign up, create a profile, access the device camera, post photo's and share images with friends based on locations around specific sites across a city.

Work Experience

Fruit of the Loom Inc. / Russell Athletic in Bowling Green, KY Associate Product Engineer

December 2016 -September 2017

- Assisted in development for wide range of safety equipment and apparel
- > Utilized SolidWorks CAD software in development of new products
- Maintained Database of all garments style info and decoration placements
- Organized and scheduled fit sessions to ensure proper fit and make changes when necessary

Fruit of the Loom Inc. / Russell Athletic in Bowling Green, KY Merchandising Systems Associate

March 2014 - September 2015

- > Transformed production artwork into product mock-ups for Uniform Builder website for 4 design cycles
- > Contributed to meetings between Design, Merchandising, and Marketing Teams
- > Collaborated with Programming Team on a daily basis to expand Russell Athletic's online presence
- > Created easy to understand technical documents to assist salespeople with the placement of custom orders
- > Created program-specific documents containing product information, units ordered, and deadlines for the production facility
- > Spearheaded the development for dynamic 3D product representations giving the salesperson and customer the ability to tailor the product to his or her desire through use of the Uniform Builder website or iPad app

AllStar Sports Photography in Bowling Green, KY Laboratory Manager / Lead Photographer

August 2007 - March 2014

- Responsible for inventory, product design, staff responsibilities, equipment maintenance, and training
- > Designed all products for 28 design cycles including, but not limited to, plaques, posters, and sublimated products
- > Supervised a team of event coordinators, photographers, and photographer assistants for over 500 Picture Days
- > Ensured a consistent and exceptional client experience through the execution of policies and procedures by all team members
- ➤ Implemented QR Code scanning for an order entry system
- Designed and produced laser cut and engraved products

Rainbow Studios in Phoenix, AZ Associate Level Designer

April 2006 - December 2006

- Created 3D terrains and race tracks based on input from the design team and beta testers
- > Participated in brainstorming meetings, blueprints, design, beta testing, and final handoff to the environment team
- Served as model motocross rider for various audio recordings
- Moderated company message board to provide consumers with technical support and product information

Development Technologies and Skills

HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript | NodeJS | ReactJS | Bootstrap | MySQL | Heroku | AWS | GitHub | React-Native

Additional Skills

- Proficiency in Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator
- Novice photography and videography skills
- 3D Modeling on an intermediate level. Software applications include: Blender, 3d Studio Max, Maya, Substance Painter/Designer